<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Blogs - A Collection of My Written and Co-directed Works Across Various Companies on Ricardo G. Sousa</title>
    <link>https://rjgsousa.github.io/posts/professional/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Blogs - A Collection of My Written and Co-directed Works Across Various Companies on Ricardo G. Sousa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 15:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rjgsousa.github.io/posts/professional/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Transform Your Bottom Line: Why Virtual Try-On Technology Is No Longer Optional</title>
      <link>https://rjgsousa.github.io/posts/professional/seeonme/roi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rjgsousa.github.io/posts/professional/seeonme/roi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With U.S. retailers losing over $25 billion annually to online apparel returns, the traditional e-commerce model is broken. &lt;a href=&#34;https://seeonme.ai/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;SeeOnMe&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s latest analysis reveals how Virtual Try-On (VTON) technology isn&amp;rsquo;t just solving the fit crisis—it&amp;rsquo;s revolutionizing retail profitability. From dramatically reducing return rates to boosting conversion through customer confidence, VTON delivers measurable ROI that forward-thinking retailers can&amp;rsquo;t afford to ignore. Discover why the most innovative companies are growing 16% faster than their competitors and how SeeOnMe&amp;rsquo;s advanced 3D persona technology is leading this retail revolution. The question isn&amp;rsquo;t whether you can afford to implement VTON—it&amp;rsquo;s whether you can afford not to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conversational Commerce: An Introduction</title>
      <link>https://rjgsousa.github.io/posts/professional/farfetch/conversational-commerce/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 06:00:23 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rjgsousa.github.io/posts/professional/farfetch/conversational-commerce/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In April 2020 I have started working on a new project to revolutionize how customers shop. For that purpose, we have written a blog post introducing Farfetch Chat (previously known as iFETCH), a conversational AI technology with multimodal capabilities developed by FARFETCH in collaboration with Carnegie Mellon University (CMU), Instituto Superior Técnico (IST), and Universidade Nova de Lisboa (NOVA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farfetch Chat aimed to revolutionize the online high-fashion sector by providing a &amp;ldquo;physical store&amp;rdquo;-like experience through natural interaction using both textual and visual data. The project focused on four pillars: natural language understanding and generation, dialogue management, product catalog and multimodal knowledge base, and product retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
